<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Median on Mahesha Godekere</title>
    <link>/categories/median/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Median on Mahesha Godekere</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/median/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Tendency</title>
      <link>/notes/central.tendency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/central.tendency/</guid>
      <description>Central tendency is &amp;quot;the statistical measure that identifies a single value as representative of an entire distribution&amp;quot;. It aims to provide an accurate description of the entire dataset. It is the single value that is most representative of the dataset.
The mean, median and mode are the three commonly used measures of central tendency.
 Mode: is a value/range that occurred with the highest frequency. Median: is the number that lies in the middle of a list of ordered numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributions</title>
      <link>/notes/distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/distributions/</guid>
      <description>Observing the distribution and their characteristics have particular importance in statistics. Distributions describes
  the data central tendency behaviour dispersion identify clusters, peaks and gaps   Normal Distribution The normal distribution, also known as the Gaussian or standard normal distribution, is the distribution that all of its values in a symmetrical fashion, and most of the results are situated around the distribution mean.
Normally distribution is perfectly symmetric around its mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPynb Test</title>
      <link>/notes/a.test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/a.test/</guid>
      <description>1: Linear regression - Introduction&amp;#182;     A simple linear function&amp;#182;To understand Machine Learning concepts , consider a simple linear function of x as below:
$ y = f(x) $ &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (1) ... simple linear function
$ x $ = Input variable / Feature $ y $ = Output variable / Target variable
    Supervised Machine Learning algorithms outputs a hypothesis, which maps x to y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kurtosis</title>
      <link>/notes/kurtosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/kurtosis/</guid>
      <description>Kurtosis is a measure of whether the data are heavy-tailed or light-tailed relative to a normal distribution. That is, data sets with high kurtosis tend to have heavy tails, or outliers. Data sets with low kurtosis tend to have light tails, or lack of outliers.
In effect, Kurtosis explains whether the samples concentrate too much at the centre or not.
A kurtosis value near 0 indicates that the data follow the normal distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Distribution with Python</title>
      <link>/notes/stat-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/stat-distribution/</guid>
      <description>Click to view Gist...</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>